Guide to the Ellen Van Volkenburg and Maurice Browne papers vvb
University of Michigan Library (Special Collections Research Center)
- Theatrical Work
  - Playbills
    - Maurice Browne and Ellen Van Volkenburg playbills
      - Maurice Browne and Ellen Van Volkenburg playbills (Great Britain)
        - Deirdre of the Sorrows (Box 22)
        - Distinguished Gathering (Box 22)
        - A Doll's House (Box 22)
        - Double Door (Box 22)
        - The Duchess of Malfi (Box 22)
        - The Duke in Darkness (Box 22)
        - Fire (Ernita Lascelles) (Box 22)
        - Full House (Box 22)
        - Fuller, Rosalind (Box 22)
        - Gentlemen's Relish (Box 22)
        - The Gift of Ko Feng (Box 22)
        - Glimpse of Reality (Box 22)
        - Good Afternoon (Box 22)
        - The Green Goddess (Box 22)
        - Green Pastures (Box 22)
        - Hamlet (Box 22)
        - Happy and Glorious (Box 22)
        - Hobson's Choice (Box 22)
        - I Lived with You (Box 22)
        - The Improper Duchess (Box 22)
        - Interference (Box 22)
        - International Season (Box 22)
        - Journey's End (Great Britain productions), 2 folders (Box 22)
          Includes autographed programs and signed cast lists.
        - Men About the House (Box 22)
        - Muted Strings (Box 22)
        - The New Gossoon (Box 22)
        - Of Gods and Men (Box 22)
        - Othello (Box 22)
          With Paul Robeson in the title role.
        - Ourselves Alone (Box 22)
        - Parker, Frank (Box 22)
        - A Party for Christmas (Box 22)
        - People in Love (Arthur Reid) (Box 22)
        - La Prisonnière (Édouard Bourdet) (Box 22)
          English version by Gilbert Wakefield.
        - Punchinello (John Hastings Turner) (Box 22)
        - Rebecca (Box 22)
        - The Secret Life (Box 22)
        - The Ship (Box 22)
        - Smale, Phyllis (Box 22)
        - The Springtime of Others (Box 22)
        - Spring Tide (Box 22)
        - Street Scene (Box 22)
        - The Sulky Fire (Box 22)
        - Tobias and the Angel (Box 22)
        - Tomorrow's Sun (Box 22)
        - Three Blind Mice (Box 22)
        - The Venetian (Clifford Bax) (Box 22)
        - Viceroy Sarah (Box 22)
        - Die Wanderbühne in Lessing's Minna Von Barnhelm (Box 22)
        - We Are the People (Box 22)
        - White Secrets (Box 22)
        - Wigman, Mary (Box 22)
        - Wings over Europe (Box 22)
        - The Women of Ghent (Box 22)
        - You Never Can Tell (Box 22)
      - Journey's End international playbills, 1929-1930 and undated (Box 22)
        Playbills for productions in Paris, Calcutta, Nairobi, and other locations.
    - Other playbills and programs
      - Theatre programs, 1924 (Box 22)
      - Playbills alphabetical file, 24 folders (Box 22, Box 23)
      - Playbills folders with Maurice Browne's notes (Box 23)
      - Puppet theatre programs (Box 23)
      - Dinner menus, 1930s (Box 23)
        Menus for dinners prepared by Maurice Browne in London.
  - Printing plates
    - Portraits of Ellen Van Volkenburg, 3 items (Box 24)
      Photoengraving plates. Various sizes.
    - Sketch of Ellen Van Volkenburg (Box 24)
    - Portraits of Maurice Browne, 2 items (Box 24)
      Photoengraving plates.
    - Portrait of Ellen Van Volkenburg and Maurice Browne (Box 24)
      Photoengraving plate.
    - Portrait of Helen of Troy (Box 24)
      Photoengraving.
    - King of the Jews scene (Box 24)
      Depicts three figures.
    - Medea title page plate (Box 24)
    - Medea actress (Box 24)
      Depicts a woman standing at a table: "Designed in the manner of Aubrey Beardsley, by Jan Stedman".
    - Medea: Ellen Van Volkenburg (Box 24)
      Copper engraving.
    - Medea (Box 24)
      Engraving with a floral border.
    - Medea scene (Box 24)
      Depicts five figures on the set.
    - The Mother of Gregory title page plate (Box 24)
    - The Mother of Gregory (Box 24)
      Depicts a spinning wheel.
    - Drawing of a woman (Box 24)
    - Portrait of a woman (Box 24)
    - Portrait of two women in robes (Box 24)
    - Portrait of a woman in robes (Box 24)
    - Portrait of a woman and child (Box 24)
    - Portrait of a woman and child (Box 24)
    - Portrait of a woman and child (Box 24)
    - "The Maurice Browne Theatre Association" (Box 24)
    - Small design featuring a face (Box 24)
    - Circular design (Box 24)
    - Chicago Little Theatre logo, 9 items (Box 24)
      Various sizes.
    - Tree design, 2 items (Box 24)
    - Decorative borders (Box 24)
      Four borders with geometric designs.
    - Unidentified plates, 4 items (Box 24)
    - An Evening with Columbine: A Whimsical Fantasy (Box 25)
    - Chicago Little Theatre news articles, 2 items (Box 25)
      Two text blocks with photoengravings and illustrations.
    - Chicago Little Theatre title text (Box 25)
    - Chicago Little Theatre seating chart (Box 25)
    - Chicago Little Theatre "Affiliated with the Incorporated Stage Society", 2 items (Box 25)
    - Chicago Little Theatre illustration (Box 25)
      Featuring candles and a spiderweb.
    - Chicago Little Theatre illustration (Box 25)
      Featuring a house.
    - Chicago Little Theatre invitation (Box 25)
      Invitation to a special matinee performance.
    - Chicago Little Theatre design (Box 25)
      Features a peacock.
    - Chicago Little Theatre illustration (Box 25)
      Features a somking man.
    - Trojan Women: Andromache (Box 25)
    - Trojan Women engraving (Box 25)
      Features a stage design.
    - Trojan Women title illustration, 5 items (Box 25)
    - Trojan Women (Box 25)
      Photogengraving. Features four women.
    - Trojan Women souvenir program (Box 25)
    - Program illustrations, 3 items (Box 25)
    - Man with sword and shield (Box 25)
    - Two women in front of a window (Box 25)
    - Woman in a window, 5 items (Box 25)
    - Women and soldiers (Box 25)
    - Metal strips, 6 items (Box 25)
    - Unidentified images, 5 items (Box 25)
  - Prompt books
    - The American (Box 26)
    - Aria da Capo (Box 26)
    - B. J. One, 8 folders (Box 26)
    - Badger's Green (Box 26)
    - Bridge of Sighs (Box 26)
    - Caviare (Box 26)
    - Charles and Mary, 2 folders (Box 26)
    - Dance, Damn You, Dance! (Box 26)
    - The Dark Saint, 2 folders (Box 26)
    - The Devil's Sabbath (Oversize 2)
    - A Doll's House, 2 folders (Box 27)
    - The Duchess of Malfi (Box 27)
    - Eastward in Eden (Box 27)
    - Electra (Box 27)
    - Fire, 3 folders (Box 27)
    - Grotesques (Box 27)
    - Guilty Souls, 2 folders (Box 27)
    - Happy and Glorious (Box 27)
    - The Hindu Gods (Oversize 2)
    - Improper Duchess, 2 folders (Box 27, Box 28)
    - Iphigenia in Aulis, 1934 (Box 28)
      Includes holograph notes and revisions. Accompanied by rehearsal schedule, light plot, and costume budget. Related to the Cornish School.
    - Journey's End
      - Journey's End prompt copies, 7 folders (Box 28)
      - Journey's End receipts, 1929 (Box 28)
      - Journey's End materials, 1929 (Box 29)
    - The Last Flame (Box 29)
    - Lemon Drops (Box 29)
    - Look Homeward, Angel (Box 29)
    - The Masked Ball (Box 29)
    - The Master Builder (Box 29)
    - Medea, 3 folders (Box 29)
    - A Midsummer Night's Dream (Box 29)
    - Muted Strings (Box 29)
    - My Friend from India (Box 29)
    - The New Gossoon (Box 29)
    - Othello, 3 folders (Box 29, Box 30)
    - The Philanderer (Box 30)
    - Punchinello, 2 folders (Box 30)
    - Quiet Wedding (Box 30)
    - The Scarecrow (Box 30)
    - A Scrap of Paper (Box 30)
    - The Seventh Eye of the Seventh Moon (Box 30)
    - The Ship (Box 30)
    - The Tidings Brought to Mary (Box 30)
    - Tobias and the Angel, 2 folders (Box 30)
    - The Trojan Women (Box 30)
    - Twelfth Night (Box 30)
    - Unknown Warrior, 2 folders (Box 30)
    - The Venetian, 3 folders (Box 31, Oversize 2)
    - Viceroy Sarah, 2 folders (Box 31)
    - Virgin Territory (Box 31)
    - We Are the People prompt copies and notes (Box 31)
    - White Secrets (Box 31)
    - The Wind and the Rain (Box 31)
    - Wings Over Europe, 2 folders (Box 31)
    - The Woman from the Voe (Box 31)
    - The Women of Ghent (Box 31)
    - You and I (Box 31)
  - Puppets
    - Puppets notebook (Box 32)
    - A Midsummer Night's Dream puppet show publicity materials (Box 32)
      Related to a show in San Francisco.
    - A Midsummer Night's Dream puppet show contract (Box 32)
    - Punch and Judy show materials (Box 32)
- Samurai Press
  - Samurai Press correspondence
    - Sabin, Arthur K. outgoing correspondence
      - Ficke, Arthur Davison, 1907-1908 (Box 32)
      - Browne, Mrs. F. H., 1907-1908 (Box 32)
      - Browne, Maurice, 1908-1956 and undated (Box 32)
    - Miles, Eustace Hamilton correspondence, ca. 1909 (Box 32)
      Addressed to Samurai Press or Arthur K. Sabin.
  - Samurai Press business and financial records
    - Arthur K. Sabin file, 1907 and undated (Box 32)
      Includes printing samples and financial records.
    - Samurai Press copyright documents and "Cranleigh Documents", 1907 and undated (Box 32)
  - Samurai Press manuscripts and proofs
    - Proposals for a Voluntary Nobility manuscript, 1907 (Box 32)
      By Maurice Browne, et al. Autograph manuscript.
    - Essays Toward a Creed for an Order of Voluntary Nobility typescript, 1907 (Box 32)
      By Maurice Browne, A. Romney Green, Harold Monro, Harold Murray, J. H. Shilton, W. F. Vernon, and H. G. Wells. Autograph typescript with handwritten corrections and additions.
    - Comments on Samurai Creeds, 1906 (Box 32)
    - The Stone Folds manuscript and proof, undated (Box 32)
      By W. W. Gibson.
    - Samurai Press proofs, undated (Box 32)
  - Samurai Press booklets and pamphlets, 1907-1908 (Box 32)
  - Samurai Press printing samples, undated (Box 32)
  - Samurai Press scrapbook, 1907 (Box 32)
    Contains press cuttings and book reviews.
  - Samurai Press announcements (Box 32)
    Includes printed and manuscript materials.
  - Samurai Press clippings, 1908-1909 and undated (Box 32)
- Personal and Family materials
  - Browne, Maurice personal materials
    - Browne, Maurice celebrity autograph letters, 1902-1926 (Box 32)
      Includes copies, summaries, and excerpts of original items.
    - "Signatures of people of distinction", 1930-1940 and undated (Box 32)
    - "Memorandum about my autobiography", 1954 (Box 32)
      To Molly Underwood and Victor Golancz, Maurice Browne's literary executors.
  - Van Volkenburg, Ellen personal materials
    - Alumni Association of the University of Michigan, 1966 (Box 32)
      Regarding a questionnaire of "distinguished women".
    - Van Volkenburg, Ellen notes, 1935-ca. 1944 and undated (Box 32)
      Includes course notes, a planning calendar, and "notes for various play ideas".
    - Van Volkenburg, Ellen genealogical information, undated (Box 32)
      Includes information about Ellen Van Volkenburg's mother's and father's families.
    - Van Volkenburg, Ellen identification cards, 1939-1955 and undated (Box 32)
    - Van Volkenburg, Ellen journals and diaries, 1910, 1928, 1930-1943, 1944-1966; 39 Volumes (Box 32, Box 33)
    - Van Volkenburg, Ellen memorabilia, 1931-1940 and undated (Box 33)
    - Van Volkenburg, Ellen notes on family coat of arms, undated (Box 33)
    - Van Volkenburg, Ellen resume and biographical information, 1945 and undated (Box 33)
    - Van Volkenburg, Ellen will and funeral plans, 1977 (Box 33)
  - Browne, Maurice and Van Volkenburg, Ellen personal materials
    - Correspondence
      Regarding Maurice Browne and Ellen Van Volkenburg's engagement.
      - Van Volkenburg, Ellen letters to R. C. Hope, 1910 (Box 34)
      - V., F. H. letters to Maurice Browne, 1910 and undated (Box 34)
      - Hope, Mary L. and Sprague, F. W. letters to Mrs. Browne, Florence, 1910 (Box 34)
      - Browne, Maurice, mother, "Nannie", and Grace R. correspondence, 1910 and undated (Box 34)
      - "Mummy" correspondence, undated (Box 34)
        Likely relates to Juliet Cooper Van Volkenburg.
    - Divorce materials
      - Browne, Maurice and Van Volkenburg, Ellen divorce papers, 1925 (Box 34)
      - Browne, Ellen (Jonson) note, ca. 1925 (Box 34)
        Note to herself regarding a possible divorce between Maurice Browne and Ellen Van Volkenburg.
      - Wood, Charles Erskine Scott and Browne, Maurice correspondence, 1924-1925 (Box 34)
        Regarding Maurice Browne and Ellen Van Volkenburg's divorce.
    - Correspondence from theatre celebrities, 1926; 2 folders (Box 34)
      Letters and telegrams from theatrical celebrities invited to L. A. banquet.
  - Browne, Frances Anna personal materials
    - Browne, Frances Anna letters, 1889-1909 and undated (Box 34)
      Letters regarding Maurice Browne's childhood.
    - Browne, Frances incoming correspondence, 1911-1913 and undated (Box 34)
      Regarding Maurice Browne.
    - Browne, Maurice school reports, 1890-1897; 2 folders (Box 34)
  - Browne, F. H. personal materials
    - Browne, F. H. correspondence
      - Browne, F. H. correspondence with Maurice Browne, 1894 (Box 34)
      - Browne, F. H. circular letters, 1888-1894 (Box 34)
      - Browne, F. H. letters of application, 1894 (Box 34)
      - Browne, F. H. letters of headmasters, 1894 (Box 34)
      - Browne, F. H. correspondence with Mr. Notcutt and the Governing Board, 1887 (Box 34)
      - Browne, F. H. correspondence regarding resignation, 1894 (Box 34)
      - Browne, F. H. correspondence with Westhorp and Mason, 1887 (Box 34)
    - Browne, F. H. documents, 1849-1894 (Box 34)
      Birth certificate, degrees, and death certificate.
    - Browne, F. H. early documents, 1859-1878 (Box 34)
    - Ipswich School materials
      - Ipswich School brochures, 1892-1893 (Box 34)
      - Ipswich Community and Neale Case materials, 1887, 1891 (Box 34)
      - Ipswich School inquiry, 1894 (Box 34)
      - Ipswich School letters to parents, 1880-1894 (Box 34)
        Mostly letterpress prints.
    - Materials related to F. H. Browne's death
      - Condolence letters to Mrs. Browne, 1894 (Box 34)
      - Funeral sermons for F. H. Browne, 1894 (Box 34)
      - Memorial for F. H. Browne, 1898 (Box 34)
    - Neale case materials
      - Browne, Maurice remarks (Box 34)
      - Beloe telegrams to F. A. B., 1886-1887 (Box 34)
      - Beloe materials (Box 34)
      - Blackmail letter, 1887 (Box 34)
      - B., F. A. letter to F. H. Browne, 1884 (Box 34)
      - Collisson item regarding the Neale case, 1887 (Box 34)
      - Correspondence regarding homes for unwed mothers, 1886 (Box 34)
      - B., F. A. inquiry regarding Neale, 1894-1897 (Box 34)
      - Neale, A. and Inspector Holland letters, 1894 (Box 34)
      - Letters regarding Neale's character, 1885-1886 (Box 34)
      - Browne, F. H. papers regarding the Neale case, 1887 (Box 34)
      - Beloe to F. A. B., 1885-1890 (Box 34)
      - Neale case transcripts (Box 34)
        Typescripts.
      - Neale letters to F. A. B., 1886-1889 (Box 34)
      - Items regarding blackmail by Dodge, 1889 (Box 34)
  - Browne, Edward Stanley personal materials
    - Browne, Edward Stanley letters, 1919-1924 and undated (Box 34)
      Includes letters to Maurice Browne.
    - Browne, Edward Stanley military records, 1832-1892 (Oversize 1)
  - Mercer, F. W. writings and illustrations
    - Mercer, F. W.: Adonais: A Lament for Keats by Shelley, 1930 (Box 34)
      Hand lettered and illustrated.
    - Mercer, F. W.: Communion Service, undated (Box 34)
      Hand lettered and illustrated. Manuscript. 21 pages.
    - Mercer, F. W.: The Heavenly Jerusalem (Box 34)
      Bound manuscript. Hand lettered and illuminated.
    - Mercer, F. W.: "An account of the ancestry of Frederick William Mercer and Louisa Elizabeth his wife, dau. of Col. Edward Stanley Browne, with the coats appertaining thereto, done by F. W. M.", ca. 1908
      Illuminated. Housed in West Stacks.
  - Browne family documents, 1808-1892 (Box 34)
  - Neligan family personal materials
    - Neligan family genealogies (Oversize 3)
    - Wilder family wills and documents, 1792-1829 (Oversize 3)
    - To Canon Neligan on his retirement, 1899 (Oversize 3)
    - Neligan family correspondence, 1794-1894 and undated (Oversize 3)
    - Neligan family miscellaneous, 1845-1858 and undated (Oversize 3)
  - Indentures, 1772-1850; 13 items
    Housed in West Stacks.
- Photographs
  - Photographs of family and friends
    - Photographs of Ellen Van Volkenburg (I), 3 folders
      - Photographs of Ellen Van Volkenburg, ca. 1883-1899; 8 items (Box 35)
      - Photographs of Ellen Van Volkenburg as a young woman, 7 items (Box 35)
      - Photographs of Ellen Van Volkenburg as an adult, 17 items (Box 35)
      - Portraits of Ellen Van Volkenburg, 1977; 3 items (Box 35)
        Two photographs and a contact sheet.
      - Ellen Van Volkenburg photograph album, 1928-1935 (Box 35)
    - Photographs of the Van Volkenburg family (II)
      - Photographs of Russell Cooper, Barbara Cooper, Imogene Van Volkenburg, Mary Whistler Wood, Harriet Whistler Wood, Louise Chase, and Juliet Van Volkenburg, 7 items (Box 35)
      - Photographs of Juliet Van Volkenburg, ca. 1880; 3 items (Box 35)
      - Photographs of Theodore Van Volkenburg, ca. 1905; 2 items (Box 35)
      - Photographs of Frank Hoyt Van Volkenburg (Box 35)
      - Photographs of William R. Wood (Box 35)
    - Photographs of Ellen and Juliet Van Volkenburg (III)
      - Photographs of Ellen Van Volkenburg, ca. 1926 (Box 35)
      - Photographs of Juliet Van Volkenburg, 2 items (Box 35)
      - Photographs of Ellen Van Volkenburg, Dorothy Gardner, and an unidentified couple, 8 items (Box 35)
      - Photographs of Ellen Van Volkenburg and Juliet Van Volkenburg in Pasadena and Seattle, ca. 1920-1940; 4 items (Box 35)
    - Photographs of Maurice Browne and family (IV)
      - Photograph of Maurice Browne hunting big game in India, 1905 (Box 35)
      - Photographs of Maurice Browne in infancy and childhood, 1881-1893; 8 items (Box 35)
      - Photograph of Maurice Browne acting (Box 35)
      - Photographs of Maurice Browne as a young man, 4 items (Box 35)
      - Photographs of Maurice Browne at Arlee, Montana, ca. 1919; 17 items (Box 35)
      - Photographs of Maurice Browne, Ellen Van Volkenburg, and Frances Anne Neligan Browne, 38 items (Box 35)
        34 photographs on 7 scrapbook leaves, 3 loose photographs, and 1 negative.
      - Photographs of Maurice Browne, 11 items (Box 35)
    - Photographs of the Browne family (V), 3 folders
      - Framed daguerreotype of Major George Browne (Box 35)
      - Photograph of Frederick Maurice Neligan, D.D., Eastbourne (Box 35)
      - Photograph of Florence Browne, Scarborough, Sarony (Box 35)
        Verso: "Sister of Rev. F. H. Browne".
      - Portrait of an Irish relative of Maurice Browne (Box 35)
        Chancellor, Dublin. Photographic reproduction of a painting.
      - Photograph of the Right Reverend Moore Richard Neligan (Box 35)
      - Photographs of Edward Stanley Browne and Reverend Frederick Herbert Browne gravesite, Ipswich?, 1894; 2 items (Box 35)
      - Drawing of "Fanny and Jack", Kent-Lacy Studios, Eastbourne, 1925 (Box 35)
        Verso: "'Fanny and Jack' copied from a very old photograph in 1925. F. A. B."
      - Photograph of Frederick and Marsie Browne (Box 35)
        Photograph by Robinson and Sons, Dublin. Parents of Maurice Browne.
      - Drawing of "Fanny and Lizzie", Kent-Lacy Studios, Eastbourne, 1925 (Box 35)
        Verso: "'Fanny and Lizzie' copied from a very old photograph in 1925. F. A. Browne."
      - Photograph of Marsie Browne, Teddy, and Dorothy (Box 35)
        Photographed by Alfred H. Cade, Ipswich.
      - Photograph of Don and Dorothy (Box 35)
        Photograph by A. H. Cade, Ipswich. Verso: "Maurice and Dorothy at a VERY early age."
      - Photographs of Frankie Browne and Babette Philipps, 1911; 2 items (Box 35)
        Photographs by Rapid Art Photography, Eastbourne.
      - Photographs of Frankie Browne, 1911; 2 items (Box 35)
      - Photographs of Frances Anna (Neligan) Browne, 12 items (Box 35)
      - Photographs of Dorothy E. (Browne) Hill and Frances H. Browne, 1902 and undated; 3 items (Box 35)
      - Photograph of Maurice Browne as a child with Dorothy Elizabeth Browne, Frances Anna (Neligan) Browne, Edward Stanley Browne, and Frances Helen Browne, ca. 1894-1895 (Box 35)
      - Photographs of Marsie Browne, Margaret Ellen, and Praxy, 1924 and undated (Box 35)
        4 photographs pasted on a single sheet.
      - Photographs of Frederick H. Browne, 4 items (Box 35)
    - Photographs of Maurice Browne, Ellen Van Volkenburg, and others (VI)
      - Photographs of Maurice Browne and Ellen Van Volkenburg, 9 items (Box 35)
      - Photographs of Maurice Browne and Ellen Van Volkenburg in Oregon, 1923; 34 items (Box 35)
      - Photographs of Maurice Browne and Ellen Van Volkenburg, ca. 1915; 4 items (Box 35)
        3 photographs and 1 negative.
      - Photographs of Maurice Browne, Ellen Van Volkenburg, and Molly Underwood, 1951; 9 items (Box 35)
      - Photographs of Maurice Browne, Ellen Van Volkenburg, and Juliet (Cooper) Browne, undated; 4 items (Box 35)
        4 photographs in a leather folder.
    - Photographs from Nellita, Washington (VII)
      - Photographs of Ellen Van Volkenburg, Maurice Browne, Mr. Breuger, Mrs. Breuger, Alexander Greene, and Mrs. Holm, 1910-1918 and undated; 19 items (Box 35)
      - Photographs of Nellita and Hood Canal, Washington, ca. 1918; 15 items (Box 35)
        Includes photographs of Maurice Browne and Ellen Van Volkenburg.
      - Photographs of Maurice Browne and Ellen Van Volkenburg at Nellita, Washington, and in Oregon, ca. 1918; 83 items (Box 35)
        81 photographs and 2 photographic reproductions.
    - Group photographs (VIII)
      - Photographs of Maurice Browne, Ellen Van Volkenburg, Mary Whistler Wood, Jeannette Durno, Elizabeth Goodrich, Grace Reynolds, John Cowper Powys, Juliet Van Volkenburg, Arthur Davison Ficke, and Mary (Reynolds) Aldis, ca. 1909-1912; 29 items (Box 35)
        Note on envelope (by Ellen Van Volkenburg): "Chicago about 1909-1910-1912 (1 photo 1910 of Villa Trollope in Florence where Maurice Browne and I met)"
      - Photographs of Maurice Browne, Ellen Van Volkenburg, John Cowper Powys, Mary Whistler Wood, and Mrs. "Mummy" Van Volkenburg, ca. 1911; 3 items (Box 35)
        Photographs by Morton Postal Photo Studio, Chicago.
    - Photographs of friends (IX)
      - Photographs of John Cowper Powys, 4 items (Box 35)
      - Photographs of Maurice Browne, Ellen Van Volkenburg, John Cowper Powys, Raymond Jonson, Vera Jonson, James Stephens, Mary Reynolds Aldis, and Mellody Farm, 21 items (Box 35)
    - Photographs of Friends (X), 5 folders
      - Photographs of Ellen Van Volkenburg, Mrs. Van Volkenburg, Bess Goodrich, and Jeannette Durno, 4 items (Box 36)
      - Group photograph, undated (Box 36)
        Ellen Van Volkenburg within a group of 23 people.
      - Group photographs, 1954-1957 and undated; 5 items (Box 36)
        Includes Ellen Van Volkenburg, Dorothy Mongan, Nancy Wilson Ross Young, Beatrice Straight Cookson, Grace Reynolds, Irene Carter, Nannie Shrope, and Jane Cochrane.
      - Photographs of Ellen Van Volkenburg, Mollie Underwood, and Harold Gosling at Quarrenden, 1957; 5 items (Box 36)
      - Daguerreotype of Ellen Van Volkenburg as a young girl, with a friend (Box 36)
        On tin.
      - Photographs of Ellen Van Volkenburg, Hazel Pearse, Jesse Reitze, Christine Hudson, and Charles Hudson, ca. 1927 and undated; 5 items (Box 36)
      - Photographs of John Cowper Powys and Arthur Davison Ficke, ca. 1927; 6 items (Box 36)
        3 photographs and 3 negatives.
      - Photographs of Maurice Browne, Ellen Van Volkenburg, and Alexander Greene, 1912-1914 and undated; 7 items (Box 36)